<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="5" moduleid="289" modulename="book" contextid="1829">
  <book id="5">
    <name>Module 2, Session 2 Subtopics</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;text&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1383934152</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1385405084</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="27">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Session 2: Apply Guidelines for Planning for Instruction</title>
        <content>&lt;h3&gt;Planning for Integrating Technology&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of Session 1, you downloaded the Technology Integration Action Plan template and started completing Part 1. In this session, you will use &lt;strong&gt;Part 2 – Planning for Integrating Technology&lt;/strong&gt; of the Technology Integration Action Plan, to map out your own individual plan to integrate a particular technology tool into a lesson you provide. The action plan is designed to help you think through the considerations for planning for the integration of technology into a specific unit or lesson that you teach. This includes what technology tool to select that maximizes the improvement of instruction and student learning, as well as your comfort level in using that particular tool in the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t done so already, &lt;span style="color: #000000;"&gt;download the &lt;a href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Tech_Integration_Action_Plan_FILLABLE.pdf" target="blank"&gt;Technology Integration Action Plan&lt;/a&gt;. Locate &lt;/span&gt;the beginning of &lt;strong&gt;Part 2 – Planning for Integrating Technology&lt;/strong&gt;, and continue to the next screen.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1383935279</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="28">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>1</subchapter>
        <title> Planning for Integrating Technology</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;In the previous session, you reflected on your students’ goals, technology skills, and level of access to technology devices. In this session, you will reflect on your own technology abilities as a teacher and your teaching goals. When filling out the &lt;a href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Tech_Integration_Action_Plan_FILLABLE.pdf" target="blank"&gt;Technology Integration Action Plan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Part 2 – Planning for Integrating Technology&lt;/strong&gt;, you will reflect on your own abilities, teaching goals, and how to progress to where you want to be with both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where Am I Now?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Consider the technology tools listed in the Technology section in Part 1 of the Technology Integration Action Plan. How comfortable are you in integrating the use of those tools in the classroom?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where Do I Want To Be?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Choose a technology tool you would like to explore further in your professional development. Where do you want to be in your comfort level with using that tool in your classroom? How do you plan on learning more about that tool and how to use the tool to improve instruction and deepen student learning?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timeline for Professional Development and Implementation.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;What are my milestones for learning about the technology tool and integrating the tool in the unit or lesson? If my students are unfamiliar with the tool, what is my plan for teaching my students about how to use the tool?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assessment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; How will I measure if the technology tool is improving instruction or deepening student learning?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a sample completed Technology Integration Action plan, &lt;a href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Tech_Integration_Action_Plan_EXAMPLE.pdf" target="blank"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox" style="margin-bottom: 30px; margin-top: 30px;"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learn More About It&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Technology is continuously evolving and it is hard to keep up with all the new tools and updates to tools coming out daily. This provides an opportunity to learn from your peers who may be exploring these new tools. Connect with adult educators in the field in &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/group/technology-and-learning"&gt;LINCS Technology and Learning Group&lt;/a&gt; and post a question about a technology tool you would like to learn more about!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1383936264</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="29">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>1</subchapter>
        <title>Reflections from Adult Education Instructors</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Effectively integrating technology in the classroom requires thoughtful planning and preparation with consideration for your students, your unit or lesson objectives, your teaching strategies, and the technology tools you plan on using to implement your strategies. In this session, you will listen to two adult education instructors as they share their own personal experiences in planning for the integration of technology into their classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After listening to their experiences, you will have the opportunity to reflect on your own experiences with utilizing technology in the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1383936319</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="30">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>1</subchapter>
        <title>Reflection from an Adult Basic Education (ABE) Instructor</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="131" height="130" style="float: right;" alt="photograph of Cynthia Bell" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/CynthiaBell.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to Cynthia Bell as she reflects on a writing lesson she taught where she utilized the technology tool, Facebook, as a platform for her students to share their writing. Cynthia has been an adult education instructor for the past eight years, and is currently a professional development associate and one of two technology integration specialists at the Literacy Assistance Center (LAC) in New York City. She teaches the numeracy series workshops at the LAC, which focus on giving instructors a deeper content knowledge to accompany their pedagogical skills and co-facilitates the LAC’s High School Equivalency prep certificate program. She holds a master’s degree in English education from New York University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Reflection%201%20ABE%20Class%20v2.m4a"&gt;Reflection%201%20ABE%20Class%20v2.m4a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read the transcript of the audio recording, &lt;a href="$@PAGEVIEWBYID*290@$" target="_blank"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox" style="margin-bottom: 30px; margin-top: 30px;"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Stop and Reflect&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What two technology tools did Cynthia try to implement with her students in the classroom? What were the observed benefits of using one tool over another? What are some limitations of both tools?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share your reflection with your peers in the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/discussion/online-course-integrating-technology-adult-education-classroom"&gt;LINCS Technology and Learning Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1383936336</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="31">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>1</subchapter>
        <title>Reflection from an English for Speakers of Other Languages (ESOL) Instructor</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="133" height="151" style="float: right;" alt="photograph of Nell Eckersley" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/NellEckersley.jpg" /&gt;Listen to Nell Eckersley share how she incorporated the technology tool, Pinterest, into her ESOL lesson on autobiographies. Nell Eckersley works at the Literacy Assistance Center (LAC) in New York City as the director of the New York State Education Department’s Regional Adult Education Network, and as the subject matter expert moderator of the LINCS Community Technology and Learning Group. Nell began her career in adult education as an English as a second language (ESL) teacher, becoming an ESL program director in 1998. The main focus of her work is incorporating digital literacy into adult teaching and learning, using social media as a catalyst. She holds a master’s degree in public administration from Columbia University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Reflection%202%20ESOL%20Class.m4a"&gt;Reflection%202%20ESOL%20Class.m4a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To read the transcript of the audio recording, &lt;a href="$@PAGEVIEWBYID*291@$" target="_blank"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox" style="margin-bottom: 30px; margin-top: 30px;"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Stop and Reflect&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did Nell’s use of Pinterest in the lesson on autobiographies enhance and extend student learning?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Share your reflection with your peers in the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/discussion/online-course-integrating-technology-adult-education-classroom"&gt;LINCS Technology and Learning Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1383936407</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="32">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>1</subchapter>
        <title>Activity - Reflection</title>
        <content>&lt;div class="graybox" style="margin-bottom: 30px; margin-top: 30px;"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Stop and Reflect&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After listening to the two teacher reflections from Cynthia Bell and Nell Eckersley, consider the following: How have you approached technology in the past? With the guidelines provided in this module, what new or additional considerations will you build into your unit or lesson planning process to more effectively integrate technology into your classroom?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share your reflection with your peers in the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/discussion/online-course-integrating-technology-adult-education-classroom"&gt;LINCS Technology and Learning Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1383936438</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="33">
        <pagenum>7</pagenum>
        <subchapter>1</subchapter>
        <title>Summary</title>
        <content>&lt;h3&gt;The key points covered in this module were: &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are a couple of different approaches to integrating technology in the classroom. One effective approach is the POST Method, which focuses on People, Objectives, Strategies, and Technology, in that order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People - Who are the People you will be teaching?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objectives - What are the Objectives?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategies - What are the Strategies to achieve the objectives?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technology - What Technology supports the people, objectives and strategies?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left: 30px;"&gt;Part 1 – POST Method of the Technology Integration Action Plan provides a template to guide you through the POST Method. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After evaluating student goals and technology skills and your unit or lesson objectives and strategies, you should consider if there is a technology tool that can enhance your lesson to improve instruction or deepen student learning by making it more relevant, authentic, and challenging. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part 2 – Planning for Integrating Technology of the Technology Integration Action Plan provides guidelines on how to select the technology tool that maximizes the improvement of instruction and student learning, as well as your comfort level in utilizing that particular tool in the classroom. This part guides teachers to think through the following in relation to their own technology skills:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where Am I Now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where Do I Want To Be?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timeline for Professional Development and Implementation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assessment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #9f2c29;"&gt;Continue onto Module 3 Introduction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1383936469</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>