<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="62" moduleid="290" modulename="page" contextid="1830">
  <page id="62">
    <name>Reflection 1: Audio Transcript - ABE Instructor, Cynthia Bell</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;transcript&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;Reflection 1: Audio Transcript, ABE Class, Cynthia Bell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;I had tried using an online platform with students in the past as a place for students to interact outside of class but I found that students just didn't go there so I had stopped doing it. But when I learned about the POST Method I realized that I had gone about the project backwards. I had found a technology tool I thought looked really great and that had driven the process rather than thinking more about who my students are, what our learning objectives were, and strategies that would support achieving the outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;So I started the planning process again but this time I started by thinking about my students --what were their tech skills and how much access did they have to technology. My students were mostly in their 20s and 30s. Some had computers at home and 70 percent had smart phones or tablets. They were pretty technology savvy. They were all very busy with work, school, and family, but 85 percent were on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;One of the learning outcomes we were working on in the course was writing the five paragraph essay for the GED® test. Most of my students did very little writing outside of class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The strategy I was developing was to create an online space to share writing to help students get more comfortable with writing and reading other people's writing. I wondered if Facebook could be used for this purpose. My attempt at using a separate online platform had failed partially because it was one more place students had to go rather than meeting them where they already were. I created a Facebook group that was private just for our class and invited students to join. The few students who were not on Facebook were willing to join if I could help them make their accounts very private. We discussed how to use Facebook responsibly. The benefit of using the Facebook group included giving us a space to meet without requiring us all to be Facebook "friends." The Facebook Groups also allowed us to upload documents so students could write in some other program and upload their work, or write directly in Facebook. Students could share links to information they had found online and could "like" or comment on each other's work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Not all students used the Facebook Group the same amount, but I found that students who used it the most had been the most reluctant to write in class, and all students completed the minimum requirements of posting four pieces of writing on the group and sharing at least one comment or resource per week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The POST Method certainly helped me to plan the integration of technology in a way that was much more successful because it took into account who my students were, rather than starting off with the technology tool.  The strategies and technology tools are puzzle pieces you have to fit together, but thinking about the people first is definitely key.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>0</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:2:{s:12:"printheading";s:1:"0";s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>23</revision>
    <timemodified>1387550589</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>