<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="66" moduleid="298" modulename="page" contextid="1838">
  <page id="66">
    <name>Reflection 4: Audio Transcript - Using Bitly and QR Codes, ABE Class Level 4 (Cynthia Bell)</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;audio transcript&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;Reflection 4: Audio Transcript, Using Bitly and QR Codes, ABE Class Level 4 (Cynthia Bell)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Our program does not have a computer lab, so for a long time I thought there was no way for us to really include technology in our classes. But I noticed that many of my students had smart phones and started thinking about how we could use those in class. I surveyed the class and it turned out that nine out of the 14 students had smart phones and would be willing to use them in class. So then, I had to think through what we could do with the smart phones. My first idea was to use the smart phones to view Khan Academy videos on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;We had been discussing the economy in class and also working on percents and multiplication. Several students had voiced interest in understanding why people buy or rent homes. There was a great Khan Academy video that showed the math behind the decision to buy or rent so I thought that would be a good video to start with.  But then I saw how long the URL was to the video and I knew that was going to be a problem because it was so long.  Students could search for the video on their smart phones but I thought that would leave some people behind. So I decided to try this URL shortener I heard about at a workshop. It's called Bitly and it takes long URLs and shortens them. I shortened the link to a Bitly link. This was still going to be a little difficult for students to type into their smart phones, especially as Bitly links are case sensitive. So then I tried out making a QR Code from the Bitly link. This would make a scannable code that students could just scan with their smart phones that would take them directly to the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;To make the QR Code, I took the shortened link and added .qr at the end of it in the address bar of my browser, and then hit enter and up came the QR Code. I right clicked on the QR Code and copied it and pasted it into a Word document. I also put up the Bitly link and the title of the video. This would be my handout. The following week in class we talked about apps on smart phones and how people find and choose which apps to download. The students had a lot to say on this subject and continued discussing and sharing their favorite apps as they left class. All the students who didn't already have a QR Code reader downloaded a free version. We talked about where people had seen QR Codes in real life and if anyone had tried scanning them. One student had scanned one on her bus route, but most of the other students had been worried they would be charged money if they scanned them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;At our next lesson, I handed out the QR Code sheet and students worked in pairs to scan it and watch the video. A few students had trouble using the QR Code scanner the first time, but once they got the hang of it they were excited about how it worked. After everyone watched the video, we did the math together on the board and discussed how New York and California are similar and different. For homework, students had to search for a rental apartment and a co-op or condo for sale to bring to class so we could try the math on those. Students brought this information in and we did the math. But perhaps more exciting for me was that many of them had taken the QR Code sheet home and shown their family and friends how to scan a QR Code, and had watched the video again. Several students also used their smart phones to do their homework assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;We could have done this lesson without technology, but I don't think it would have been so rich or resonated so deeply with my students if they had read an article rather than seeing the math being done "live." I also think that the excitement around using the QR Code extended the lesson outside of class time, as students took the QR Codes home and showed other people how to use them--and ended up watching the video again. I also think using the smart phones in class for learning helped some students see that the smart phone could be used to gather information.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>0</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:2:{s:12:"printheading";s:1:"0";s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>22</revision>
    <timemodified>1387550659</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>