<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="8" moduleid="299" modulename="book" contextid="1839">
  <book id="8">
    <name>Culminating Activity and Course Conclusion</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;do not display&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1384200921</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1385405640</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="47">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Culminating Activity</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Now that you have completed all the modules in &lt;em&gt;Integrating Technology in the Adult Education Classroom&lt;/em&gt;, you will have the opportunity to apply the concepts learned from this course to redesign a unit or lesson plan you already use in your classroom by integrating technology into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Technology Integration Action Plan was developed to help you think through the considerations when planning for integrating technology. The full plan is comprised of three parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part 1 – Applying the POST Method&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part 2 – Planning for Integrating Technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part 3 – Reflecting on Integrating Technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download the complete Technology Integration Action Plan template &lt;a href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Tech_Integration_Action_PlanFILLABLE.pdf" target="blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 30px;"&gt;To help you get started, view a &lt;a href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Tech_Integration_Action_Plan_EXAMPLE.pdf" target="blank"&gt;sample&lt;/a&gt; completed Technology Integration Action Plan template.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Steps to completing the Technology Integration Action Plan:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select a unit/lesson that you currently use in your classroom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete Part 1 of the Technology Integration Action Plan on Applying the POST Method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select a technology tool to explore and integrate into your unit/lesson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete Part 2 of the Technology Integration Action Plan on Planning for Integrating Technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revise your unit/lesson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement your revised unit/lesson with your students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the completion of implementing your revised unit/lesson, assess your results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete Part 3 of the Technology Integration Action Plan on Reflecting on Integrating Technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are finished redesigning your lesson plan, we invite you to share it with others in the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/discussion/online-course-integrating-technology-adult-education-classroom"&gt;LINCS Technology and Learning Group&lt;/a&gt; in the LINCS Community. We encourage you to revisit the LINCS Technology and Learning Group periodically to learn from others and share your experiences with integrating technology.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1384203987</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="48">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Thank you!</title>
        <content>&lt;h3 class="Topic"&gt;Extended Learning in the LINCS Community&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations on completing the &lt;i&gt;Integrating Technology in the Adult Education Classroom &lt;/i&gt;course! Stay involved in the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/home"&gt;LINCS Community&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/group/technology-and-learning"&gt;LINCS Technology and Learning Group&lt;/a&gt; as you work to continue to integrate technology in your classroom. If you shared a redesigned lesson that you created in the culminating activity, we encourage you to revisit the LINCS Technology and Learning Group in a month to reflect on your progress and its effectiveness. Share what worked and what you may have changed based on your experience executing the plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the year, the LINCS Technology and Learning Group in the LINCS Community hosts discussions and activities where additional technology tools and more advanced examples of integration for instruction are introduced by the SME moderator, guest speakers, and group members. As you work toward increased technology integration in your classroom, we recommend that you continue your professional development by sharing, learning, and participating in the LINCS Technology and Learning Group. Technology is ever-evolving and being active in the LINCS Technology and Learning Group is a great way to stay current on the latest tools.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1384204020</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="49">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>1</subchapter>
        <title>Course Conclusion</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;This concludes the &lt;i&gt;Integrating Technology in the Adult Education Classroom &lt;/i&gt;course. We would like to thank the individuals and organizations who generously contributed to the design and development of this course:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nell Eckersley, Director, New York City (NYC) Regional Adult Education Network, Literacy Assistance Center, NYC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cynthia Bell, Professional Development Associate, Literacy Assistance Center, NYC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a complete list of referenced resources, websites, and tools mentioned in the course, &lt;a href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/References.pdf" target="blank"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations on completing the &lt;em&gt;LINCS Integrating Technology in the Adult Education Classroom&lt;/em&gt; course! So that we can maintain the quality of our courses, please take a moment to complete the &lt;a href="http://s-4019c7-i.sgizmo.com/s3/i-100000279-840919"&gt;course evaluation survey&lt;/a&gt;. Your feedback will ensure our courses meet your needs for professional development. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox" style="margin-bottom: 30px; margin-top: 30px;"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Access and Print Your Certificate Anytime&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To obtain your completion certificate, exit this book and return to the course main page.  Under the Conclusion section of the main page, select Completion Certificate. On the next page, select the ‘Get your certificate’ button. From there, you will be able to print your course certificate of completion.&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Literacy Information and Communication System (LINCS) science course was developed by Kratos Learning for the U.S. Department of Education, Office of Vocational and Adult Education under Contract No. ED-VAE-11-C-0048. The opinions expressed herein do not necessarily represent the positions or policies of the U.S. Department of Education, and no official endorsement by the U.S. Department of Education should be inferred. This course is in the public domain and may be used without permission.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1427790666</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>