<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="63" moduleid="291" modulename="page" contextid="1831">
  <page id="63">
    <name>Reflection 2: Audio Transcript - ESOL Class, Nell Eckersley</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;Nell Eckersley transcript&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;Reflection 2: Audio Transcript, ESOL Class, Nell Eckersley&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;I was very nervous about using technology with my students. I was as nervous about my own skills as those of my students. My class was made up of working age and older adults and the level of digital literacy varied greatly. About 40 percent had smart phones and 50 percent were on Facebook. When I learned about the POST Method I knew that I needed to take my own skills and fears into account as part of the P for people. What would I need to do for myself to help me become more comfortable?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;If I thought about my students, those who were already using technology in their own lives would really appreciate using some technology in our lessons and those not using it had children who were heavy users, leaving their parents feeling very disconnected. Also several students had asked for help to fill out online job applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;We had already been working on autobiographies which consisted of bringing in pictures cut out from magazines and using them as writing prompts. The outcomes for this project included learning vocabulary, using the present, past, conditional, and future tenses in writing, and using techniques to help one feel comfortable speaking in front of groups of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;I had seen a technology tool called Pinterest that a friend was using to gather all sorts of beautiful images from the internet. My friend showed me how to sign up for Pinterest and I quickly became comfortable using it, in fact I found it a bit addictive. I even found some boards on Pinterest with Pinterest lesson ideas that helped me explore even more and find other teachers using it. Finally, I was ready to use it with my students. I decided to try using Pinterest as the image gathering part of the autobiography project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The day before we went into the computer lab, we talked about online communities and addressed some concerns about privacy that some students had.  We talked about the specific terms used in Pinterest, such as, boards, repin, like, follow. We also discussed creating a username and password and for homework everyone had to come up with the username and password they wanted to use for Pinterest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The next day we went into the lab and everyone signed up for Pinterest.  I paired people so that a more experienced computer user was paired with a less experienced user. Once all the students were on Pinterest, they each created a board called autobiography, which they shared with me. And then we did a Google search together as a class for an image of each of their home countries. This was the first image they pinned to their boards. Then they worked in pairs to search for images of their favorite foods. For homework students had to find two more images. They could find them online or upload them. For those who did not have access to computers, we talked about the other places they could access computers like the nearby library and we also arranged for half an hour of open lab time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;All the students did their homework and some did much more than was assigned. On our next lab day the students chose one of the images and wrote a paragraph about how it connected to their lives that they then pasted into the description of the image on Pinterest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;This experience really helped me to find the value in using technology with my students. It also helped me to feel more comfortable with at least trying out new tools.  My students have shared a lot of images with one another and we have used Pinterest now for other projects including a collaborative board on what a new immigrant needs to know when they arrive in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>0</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:2:{s:12:"printheading";s:1:"0";s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>21</revision>
    <timemodified>1387550606</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>