<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="65" moduleid="297" modulename="page" contextid="1837">
  <page id="65">
    <name>Reflection 3: Audio Transcript – Email Lesson, Intermediate ESOL Class (Nell Eckersley)</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;audio transcript&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;Reflection 3: Audio Transcript, Email Lesson, Intermediate ESOL Class (Nell Eckersley)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;In my program, we had always written letters to the mayor of New York City to thank the mayor for funding us and to comment on issues in the community that the students had identified earlier. The students were intermediate level ESOL students from the former Soviet Union and Pakistan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The letter to the mayor was culmination of many separate lessons including a discussion on New York City government, the election process, advocating for your needs and wants, eliciting from students the things they like and didn't like about their community, formal letter layout, writing a biography paragraph, and various vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Our agency had gotten a new computer lab and the mayor had added to the city government website a portal to communicate with him via email, so we thought we could add sending the letter to the mayor as an email rather than a paper letter. The planning included signing up for the computer lab and identifying who had email addresses already. We discovered that several students didn't have email addresses so we did a cursory plan to add getting an email address, and then we went to the computer lab.  It turned out that some of the student who had an email address didn't know how to access them from a public computer. And for the students who needed to get email addresses, even choosing a good email address and a password could be a challenge. We also had some students who had great facility with computers and email and were quickly bored by the pace of the lesson. We also found that Gmail limited how many email addresses you could get over a certain amount of time form the same IP address which complicated the process. We did partner some of the experts with the students who needed extra coaching and eventually we got everyone on their email and they sent off their letters as emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;When we repeated this lesson with other classes, we did things a little differently. We extended the computer portion over several lessons. We spent time in our classroom helping students identify the email address they wanted (and some alternates). We also talked about how to create and remember good passwords. We required students to bring their email login credentials to class the day before the lesson in the computer lab to make sure everyone knew how to get to their email from our lab computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;I certainly reflected on the fact that something that seemed like a simple addition to an existing lesson had become a rather involved multistep process and was it worth it? Was it taking us off purpose? In the end, I think that our students really enjoyed getting email addresses. There were several Pakistani women who had computers at home that their husbands and children used, but these women had no connection to. They actually cried after they got their email accounts as they could now communicate with friends and family in their home countries. Students now email me their homework if they cannot come to class and communicate with each other to get assignments. Email has helped to build an even stronger community among the students.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>0</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:2:{s:12:"printheading";s:1:"0";s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>23</revision>
    <timemodified>1387550637</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>